Guide to the Janet Lewis Papers, 1964-1989
Department of Special Collections
Janet Lewis Papers,
1964-1989
Special Collections M0543
Lewis, Janet, 1899-.
6.75 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Janet Lewis, 1988 and 1989.
Biographical Note
American writer of many genres, including novels, short stories, poetry and librettos. Many of her friends and correspondents were at one time students or colleagues of Yvor Winters.
Scope and Content
Incoming personal and professional correspondence, including letters from William Bergsma, Gus Blaisdell, Elizabeth Daryush, Donald Davie, John Edmunds, John Fraser, Richard Freis, Charles Gullans, Thom Gunn, Maurice Lesemann, N. Scott Momaday, Grosvenor Powell, Pearl Andelson Sherry, Ann Stanford and Donald E. Stanford. Some manuscripts by Janet Lewis and others. 3 photographs. Basically an addenda to M352, the papers of Yvor Winters and Janet Lewis, with the bulk of this material dated after 1982.
Access Terms
Bergsma, William, 1921-.; Blaisdell, Gus.; Daryush, Elizabeth Bridges.; Davie, Donald.; Edmunds, John.; Fraser, John.; Freis, Richard.; Gullans, Charles B.; Gunn, Thom.; Lesemann, Maurice.; Momaday, N. Scott, 1934-.; Powell, Grosvenor, 1932-.; Sherry, Pearl Andelson.; Stanford, Ann.; Stanford, Donald E., 1913.; American literature--20th century.; Photoprints.
Container List
- Incoming Correspondence
  - Abe, Masako. Correspondence, March 1959 to [Dec. 1979]. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abramowitz, Moses. 2 ALS, Jan. 16, 1979; Jan. 19, 1982.
  - Abramson, Roberta. 1 ALS, May 5, 1978.
  - Academy of American Poets, The. Correspondence, brochures, booklets, book lists, receipts, etc., Nov. 1971 to Sept. 1981.Includes 2 poems by Barbara Thompsen, entitled Snake and Boston Fern, and 1 poem by Jennifer Hirsch, called Foolish Pleasure. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - -----. Correspondence et al., Jan. 1983 to Aug. 1983[no pm after this date]. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ackerman, Will. 1 TLS, Aug. 27, [n.y.].
  - Adams, Theodore S. Correspondence, April 1979 to Nov. 1983. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Addison-Wesley Publishing Company. 1 TLS, July 11, 1969.
  - Admiral Bristol Hospital. Correspondence et al., Dec. 1968 to Nov. 1981.
  - Ahsahta Press. Correspondence, March 1978 to Oct. 1979,and announcements of collections of modern poetry for 1978and 1975 to 1979.
  - Akard, Jeff. Correspondence and book lists, Feb. 1981 to April 1981. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - -----. Correspondence and 1 book list, April 1981 to May [1983]. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Aldrich, Mrs. Putnum. Correspondence et al., March 1977 to June 1983.Includes a review of Le Retour de Martin Guerre. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Alexander, Janet. 2 ALS, Oct. 21, 1971; Nov. 8, 1971.
  - All-media Dramatic Workshop. 1 TLS, June 22, 1976.
  - Allen, Betsy. 1 ALS, March 28, [1982].
  - Allen, Charles and Elsie. 1 ACS, April 3, 1979.
  - American Historical Company, Inc. 2 TLS, April 10, 1968; May 2, 1968.
  - American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers (ASCAP). Correspondence, writer performance records, records of quarterly distributions, lists, brochures, Dec. 1961 to 1980. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - -----. Correspondence et al., 1979 to [1983][no pm after this date]. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Amiriam, Lemyel. 1 TLS, Dec. 15, 1980. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Anaya, Kathy. 1 ALS, [n.d.].
  - Antolini, Holly. Correspondence, July 1980 to May [1983?];1 poem, signed, entitled Persimmons, Nov. 24, 1980.
  - Ariel. 1 ALS, March 3, 1980.
  - Arizona State University. Correspondence et al., Dec. 1980 to Jan. 1981.
  - Arnold, Aerol. Correspondence, Aug. 1977 to Jan. 1980.
  - Arnold, Anna Bing. Correspondence, April 1977 to March 1979.Includes other correspondence.
  - -----. Correspondence, [April 1979] to Jan. 1981. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - -----. Correspondence, Feb. 1981 to Nov. 1983[no pm after this date]. Includes other correspondence. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Babin, Vitya. 1 ACS, Jan. 1, 1983. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Badgley, Elaine. Correspondence, Sept. 1980 to Jan. 1982.
  - Baker, Dorothy. 1 TLS, [n.d.].Includes exchange of letters between Howard Baker and a public-speaking obscurantist [Sept. 16, 1966].
  - Baker, Howard. 1 ALS, April 15, 1974.
  - Baker, Mark. 1 TLS, [n.d.].
  - Bakerman, Jane S. 1 TLS, Aug. 6, 1974.
  - Bartels, Dede & Betty Estersohn. 1 TLS, March 13, 1979.
  - Barth, Bob. Correspondence et al., June 1982 to Dec. 1983.Includes poem This Shade by Suzanne J. Doyle.
  - Baumann, Susan. 2 TLS, Dec. 11, 1975; March 16, 1976. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - BC Research. Correspondence, Nov. 1980 to Feb. 1981.
  - Becker, Stephen. Correspondence, May 1971 to April 1977.Includes other correspondence.
  - Beeman, Polly. Correspondence, [July 1977] to [June 1978].
  - Bergsma, Nickie and Bill. Correspondence, [Dec. 1958] to [Dec. 1981].Includes 2 photos. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - -----. Correspondence, Jan. 1982 to Aug. 1983. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Berkman, Sylvia. 1 ALS, Feb. 10, 1983.
  - Bernies-Lasserre, Claude. 1 ALS, Nov. 22, 1977.
  - Birkin, Dimitri. 1 TLS et al., June 24, 1966.
  - Blaisdell, Gus. Correspondence, May 1968 to Oct. 1980.Includes 3 poems by Gus Blaisdell, entitled 2 Cartesian Poems (Cogito and Inside), and To a Poet. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Blau, Herbert. 1 ALS, May 11, 1967;1 photocopy of an article, Blau Becomes Disenchanted With Disney's Dream, Oct. 17, 1971. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Blau, Linda and Nathan. Correspondence et al., [March 1975] to July 1978.
  - Blau, Tara. Correspondence et al., [Nov. 1975] to Oct. [1983].Includes 1 photo.
  - Blive, Bruce and Rosie. Correspondence, Jan. 1970 to Aug. 1977. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Bode, Adolf. 1 carbon of a TLS to Peter Allen, Sept. 16, 1974.
  - Bowers, Edgar. Correspondence, Dec. [1979] to Jan. 1983.
  - [Bray?], Michele. 1 ALS, [n.d.].
  - Bray, Nancy. Correspondence et al., Aug. 1976 to Oct. 1983.
  - Brazer, Marjorie. 2 TLS, Dec. 6, 1975; Jan. 24, 1976.
  - Brick, Jackie. 1 TLS, Nov. 24., 1971.
  - Briggs, Marjorie. 2 ALS, [June 10, 1981]; Jan. 10, [n.y.].
  - Brown, Bruce Bennet. 1 TLS, Jan. 19, 1971. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Brown, Robert Bruce. 1 wedding invitation, [n.d.].
  - Buffington, Robert. Correspondence, Nov. 1979 to May 1981.
  - Bullock, Marie. 1 ALS, March 11, 1979.
  - Bundy, Barbara. Correspondence et al., July 1975 to Feb. 1981.Includes 1 photo and 1 photocopy of a talk by Barbara Bundy.
  - Burden, Jean. Correspondence, May 1978 to July 1978.
  - Burr, Carol. 1 TLS, July 10, 1983.Includes photocopy of General Questions on the Sense of Place.
  - Caldwell, Katherine. 1 ALS, Aug. 27, 1974. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - California State University, Los Angeles, The Writing Center. 1 TLS, 1 ph. TLS, Jan. 11, 1979; May 5, 1980.
  - California Writers' Club. 1 TLS, 1 brochure, July 15, 1967.
  - Campbell, Susan Glynn. 1 marriage announcement, [n.d.].
  - Capazoli, Nick. 1 TLS, April 21, 1980.Includes 1 Rilke poem, Aus einer Kindheit/From a Childhood.
  - Carcanet New Press. Correspondence et al., [Sept. 1977] to Aug. 1978.
  - Carnochan, Brigitte. Correspondence et al., [Sept. 1979] to [March 1983].Includes review of Janet Lewis Winters' works and The Remembered Landscape in the Life and Art of Janet Lewis, the abstract of an MLA talk by Brigitte Carnochan. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Carroll, Donald. 1 TLS, March 3, 1968. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Chan, Clifton. 1 ACS, 1 ALS, April 18, 1975;Christmas 1975.
  - Chenery, Holly. Correspondence et al., July 1971 to Aug. 1971.
  - Chenery, Louise. Correspondence et al., Jan. [1970] to Dec. 1971.Included a poem, For Louise', by Janet Lewis Winters. Manuscript transferred to Box 8, folder 1.
  - Chimera, Books & Records. 1 TLS, April 30, 1980. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Choitz, Ulrich. 1 ALS, [n.d.].
  - Church, Peggy Pond. Correspondence, Sept. 1979 to Oct. [1983].Includes a copy of her poem Return to a Landscape.
  - Chute, Peggi. 2 ALS, [April 28, 1978]; June 20, 1978.
  - Claire, William. Correspondence, Feb. 1967 to July 1967.
  - Clark, David R. 1 TLS, Feb. 23, 1980. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Clark, Naomi. 1 TLS, 1 ALS, Oct. 31, 1975; Nov. 11, 1977.
  - Cohen, Miriam. Correspondence, [Feb. 1970] to Sept. 1983.
  - Cohen, Mollie. 2 TLS et al., Valentine's Day, 1976; Oct. 1, 1980.
  - Collins, Martha. 2 TLS, Sept. 30, 1980; June 6, 1981.
  - Comito, Terry. Correspondence, Aug. 1979 to Oct. 1980. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Commonwealth Club, The. 1 TLS, April 21, 1982;1 list of 51th Annual Literature Medal Awards.
  - Compass, The. 1 TLS, April 27, 1978.
  - Composers Recordings. Lists of recordings, 1975 to 1982.
  - Conger, Jean. Correspondence et al., July 1976 to Aug. 1981.Includes a copy of a review of books by Christina Stead with mention of Janet Lewis Winters.
  - Connell, Evan. Correspondence, Feb. 1969 to Dec. 1969.Includes 2 reviews of The Wife of Martin Guerre by Evan Connell, carbon and ph. typescript, and a published one, entitled Genius Unobserved. Carbon typescript transferred to Box 8, folder 5.
  - Conners, Sue. Correspondence, April [1978] to May 1982. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Connor, Ann W. 1 TLS, July 11, 1983.
  - Coons, Mrs. Albert. 1 wedding invitation, Sept. 4, 1983.
  - Cooper, Mark. 1 ALS, Oct. 18, 1982.
  - Courtillot, Fran[UNK]coise. Correspondnce, April 1982 to Dec. 1982.
  - Covici, Allan. Correspondence et al., Dec. 1975to Election Day, 1978.
  - Cowley, Mrs. Malcolm. 1 TLS, Sept. 17, 1967.
  - Crawford, Connie. 1 TLS, Dec. 16, 1982.Includes 1 photo.
  - Crossley, Desne. 1 ALS, May 22, 1982. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Crossley, Elaine. 1 ALS, Sept. 18, 1975.Includes announcements of exhibits.
  - Crow, Charles. Correspondence, May 1977 to [Dec. 1982].
  - Crumly, Meg. 1 wedding invitation, 1 ALS, Feb. 26, 1983; [March 10, 1983].
  - Cuddon, J.A. 1 ALS, May 18, 1983.
  - Cunningham, Dolora. 1 ALS, Aug. 12, 1979.
  - Cunningham, Jim and Jessie. Correspondence, [Dec. 1979] to [Dec. 1982].
  - Curtis Brown, Ltd. Correspondence et al., Oct. 1964 to [Jan. 1968].Includes other correspondence. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - -----. Correspondence et al., Jan. 1968 to June 1969. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - -----. Correspondence, royalty statements, etc., July 1969 to [1982].Includes 1 carbon TL from Janet Lewis Winters and other correspondence. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Dahl, Peter & Karen, Laura, Allison. Correspondence, May 1975 to Jan. 1982. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - [Dahlgren], Odile. Correspondence et al., July 1970 to Sept. 1978.
  - Daniel, John. 1 ALS, Dec. 8, 1980.
  - Darling, Robert. Correspondence et al., Dec. 1976 to June 1981.Includes copy of The Birth of the Infanta. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Daryush, Elizabeth. 1 ALS, 1 Christmas card, April 10, 1974; [Dec. 8, 1976].
  - Davie, Diana & Keith. 1 ALS, Aug. 21, 1975.
  - Davie, Donald. Correspondence, Feb. 1965 to Dec. 1981.Includes Songs from Night of Miracles.
  - Davie, Doreen. Correspondence, Dec. 1966 to Nov. 1980. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - -----. Correspondence, Nov. 1980 to March 1983[no pm after this date]. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Davies, Mrs. Louise. 1 ALS, Aug. 10, [1981]. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Davis, Dick. Correspondence, Nov. 1979 to Feb. 1982.
  - Davis, Esther H. Correspondence et al., Feb. 1967 to Dec. 1981.
  - Davis, Nathalie Zemon. Correspondence et al., May 1981 to June 1984.
  - Day, A. Grove. 1 TLS, Dec. 3, 1988.
  - Dayle, Suzane. 2 ALS, June 20, 1982; Dec. 3, 1983.
  - Dermont, Joanne. Correspondence, Oct. [1973] to Oct. 1980[no pm after this date]. Includes other correspondence. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Dermont, Joe. Correspondence et al., Sept. 1978 to [April 1979].Includes 2 photos and letters by Joanne Dermont. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - -----. Correspondence et al., July 1979 to April 1980.Includes 1 photo. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - -----. Correspondence, Oct. 1980 to Oct. 1982. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - -----. Correspondence et al., Feb. 1983 to Nov. [1983][no pm after this date]. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - DeSoto, Hisaye. Correspondence, Nov. 1968 to Dec. 1982. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Despres, Joanna. 2 ACS, March 3, 1981; May 27, 1981. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Dessau, Dorothy. 1 TLS, Feb. 2, 1970.
  - D'Evelyn, David. 2 ALS, Feb. 12, 1979; Oct. 23, 1979.Includes 1 issue of The Meridian Line, Fall 1979.
  - D'Evelyn, Thomas. 2 TLS, Aug. 1, 1978; Nov. 4, 1980.
  - DeVoney, Bessie. 1 TLS, Sept. 5, 1964.Includes 1 newspaper article. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Dickey, R.P. Correspondence et al., [May 1975] to Aug. 1975.Includes 1 carbon TLS from Janet Lewis Winters and other correspondence.
  - Djerassi, Carl. 2 TLS, Dec. 9, 1980; April 6, 1981.
  - Djerassi, Norma. 2 ALS, Jan. 4, 1970; April 4, [1979].
  - Doan, Alby. 1 ALS, [April 24, 1980].
  - Dominican College. Correspondence et al., Aug. 1976 to March 1977. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Doubleday. Correspondence et al., Nov. 1964 to Oct. 1968. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - -----. Correspondence et al., Oct. 1968 to March 1980. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Dragin, Jan. 1 ALS, [Feb. 18, 1964]. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Draper, Dorothy. 1 ALS, [April 2, 1982].
  - Draper, Maureen McCarthy. Correspondence, May 1978 to March 1979.Includes poems, Easter 1978, Hommage to Paul Cezanne, Fragments for Don Juan, Eating a Persimmon, After the Concert, Lines at Dawn.
  - Draper, Maureen McCarthy. Correspondence et al., June 1979 to Oct. 1983[no pm after this date]. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Dufour, Jeanne H. 1 TLS, July 27, 1978. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Dworsky, Leo Henry. 1 marriage announcement, May 8, 1964.
  - EBA School of Art. 1 TLS, July 19, 1983.Includes 1 announcement.
  - Edmunds, John. Correspondence et al., April 1967 to Sept. 1977.
  - -----. Correspondence et al., Jan. 1978 to May 1983.Includes ph. preface to Twenty-one Selected Songs, 1 ph. sheet of music, There were three kings, ph. preface to The Voyage ot Ararat. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Ellis, [---]. 1 TLS, Oct. 2, [1975]. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Emmert, Mack. 1 ACS, [Oct. 31, 1976].
  - Fabrizio, Margaret. 1 ALS, March 31, 1978.
  - Farber, Tom. 2 TLS, June 26, 1979; May 12, 1980.
  - Feferman, Anita. Correspondence, [July 1975] to [July 1983].
  - Feferman, Rachel. 1 ALS, Nov. 2, 1983.Includes material about The Rites of Winter.
  - Felstiner, John. 1 TLS, June 15, 1976.
  - Finlay, John. Correspondence, March 1969 to June 1978. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Fisher, Rebecca. 1 TLS, Feb. 21, 1976.
  - Fishman, Ronit. 1 wedding invitation, 1 ALS, Sept. 4, 1977; Oct. 9, 1977.
  - Fishman, Zehava. 1 ALS, Jan. 16, 1970.
  - Fitzgerald, B. 1 ALS, [Sept. 5, 1975].
  - Flack, Frank M. 1 TLS, Oct. 18, 1976. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Flanner, Hildegarde. Correspondence, Aug. 1971 to Dec. 1982.
  - Font, Lolly. 1 ALS, [Feb. 10, 1981].
  - Ford, Betsy Perry. 1 TLS, July 28, 1979.
  - Ford, Tre. Correspondence, Sept. 1964 to Oct. 1967. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Foreman, Paul. 2 TLS, April 28, 1974; Feb. 4, 1976.
  - Fowle, Mrs. John. 1 ALS, April 30, 1983.
  - Frazer, John. Correspondence, May 1968 to Oct. 1975.
  - Freis, Catherine. 1 ALS, March 12, 1983.Includes phone bills. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Freis, Richard. Correspondence et al., Sept. 1976 to Oct. 1977.Includes Act III, Scene 3, of The Avenging Flame and 1 carbon TLS from Janet Lewis Winters.
  - -----. Correspondence, June 1978 to June 1983.Frück, Maggie. 1 ALS, July 31, 1982. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Gale Research Center. 1 TLS, April 9, 1976.Includes receipts, copyright material. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Garcia, George Elmer. 1 wedding invitation, March 25, 1975.
  - Garcia-Zvava, Rebecca. 1 ALS, May 18, 1975.
  - Gardiner, Margaret. 1 ALS, April 13, 1983.
  - Gates, Doris. Correspondence, Jan. 1966 to Jan. 1969.Includes other correspondence. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Gerlach, Murney Mintzer. 1 marriage announcement, July 15, 1978. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Gevers, Louis. 1 ALS, July 29, 1983.
  - Ghosh, Arati. 1 ALS, Dec. 22, 1960.
  - Gibbons, Reginald. Correspondence, Feb. 1982 to May 1982.
  - Ginn & Company. Correspondence, Feb. 1967 to Oct. 1968.Includes other correspondence.
  - Gioia, Dana. Correspondence et al., Nov. 1981 to Jan. 1982.Includes a review of Janet Lewis Winters' Poems Old and New: 1918-1978. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Gioia, Dorothy. 1 ALS, Aug. 7, 1982.
  - Givner, Caroline. 2 TLS, June 15, 1979; June 30, 1979.
  - Glaeseman, Caroline. Correspondence, Aug. [1976] to Sept. [1976].
  - Gleason, Vee. Correspondence, Dec. 1976 to March 1979[no pm after this date].
  - Glenn, Barbara. Correspondence, Jan. 1980 to [July 1982].Includes An Interview with Ann Stanford and a note on Barbara Glenn. (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Gold, Melissa. 2 ALS, June 11, [1980]; July 17, 1980.
  - Goldberg, Miriam. 2 ALS, June 20, 1982; April 30, 1983.Imcludes poem Anniversay number three, dialogue Birth Seen, poem My love. (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Victor Gollancz, Ltd. 1 TLS, Nov. 25, 1971.Includes royalty statement and 1 carbon TLS from Janet Lewis Winters.
  - Goodman, Jeffrey. 1 TLS, March 2, [1973].Includes 2 notes, poems To My Children, The Beginning, The Waking, The Radio, Silence.
  - Graff, Jerry. 1 ALS, 1 TLS, July 19, 1970; April 21, 1975.
  - Greenberg, Barbara. 1 ALS, Jan. 26, 1982. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Greenberg, Joanne [Mrs. Albert Greenberg]. 1 ALS, July 12, 1976.
  - Greenwood Press. 1 TLS, Nov. 16, 1976.
  - Grega, Jeanne. 1 ALS, Dec. 2, 1980.
  - Gregory, Horace. 1 TLS, [May 9, 1977].
  - Griffin, Gladys. Correspondence, [Oct. 1977] to Feb. [1983].
  - Grupp, Mr. and Mrs. James Bromily. 1 birth announcement, [Jan. 1968].
  - Guerard, Albert. 1 TLS, June 13, 1983.
  - Guerard, Collot. 1 ALS, Nov. 24, 1976.
  - Guerard, Therina. 1 ACS, Aug. 27, [n.y.].
  - Guidoux, Anita. 1 ALS, Oct. 6, 1975. (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Guidoux, Kathy. 1 ALS, Oct. 6, 1975.
  - Gullans, Charles. Correspondence et al., July 1977 to Aug. 1983.
  - Gulotta, Vincenzo. Correspondence, Oct. 1971 to Oct. 1976. (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - -----. Correspondence, Nov. 1977 to July 1980. (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Gunn, Cynthia Fry. 1 TLS, Aug. 28, 1980.
  - Gunn, Thom. Correspondence, Sept. 1979 to April 1982.
  - Gurian, Paul R. 1 TLS, Dec. 9, 1972.
  - Hall, Jenny Krendel. 1 ALS, Sept. 6, 1980.
  - Hamovitch, Mitzi. Corespondence, March 1976 to Oct. 1980. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - -----. Correspondence et al., Aug. 1982 to March 1983.Includes flyers, ph. book reviews, also about The Invasion by Janet Lewis Winters. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - -----. Correspondence et al., [March 1983] to [July 1983].Includes a review of The Return of Martin Guerre, other reviews and an article by Doris Grumbach. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Handly, Helen. 1 ALS, June 24, 1981.
  - Hannotte, Dean. 1 TLS, Aug. 24, 1980.
  - Hardovin, Pat. 2 TLS, May 2, 1979; Aug. 19, 1983.Includes a review of The Return of Martin Guerre.
  - Hargraves, Michael. 1 TLS, Aug. 18, 1979. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Harper & Row. 1 TLS, Dec. 13, 1974.
  - Harris, Josephine. Correspondence, April 1969 to Sept. 1978.Includes other correspondence.
  - -----. Correspondence et al., Nov. 1978 to Oct. 1981.Includes ph. of fore-words and epigraph to Writers' Wives. (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Harris, Mark. Correspondence et al., Jan. 1974 to Jan. 1981.
  - Harrison, Buffy [Mrs. John]. 1 ALS, Jan. 21, 1970. (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Harvey, Gordon. 1 TLS, Oct. 7, 1983.
  - Hayes, Ann. 1 ALS, Nov. 30, 1981.
  - Henderson, Alva. 1 invitation to his birthday party, May 6, [n.y.].
  - Hendry, Diana. 1 ALS, 1 TLS, July 12, 1982; June 17, 1983.
  - Henneberger, Sally. 1 ALS, Sept. 23, [n.y.].
  - Henrichsen, Marg. 1 TLS, 1 ALS, Feb. 21, 1976; May 3, 1976.Included 3 photos, transferred to Box 8, folder 7.
  - Manuscripts of poems transferred to Box 8, folders 3 and 4.
  - Inglis, Fred. 1 ALS, July 18, 1968. (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - International Authors and Writers Who's Who, The. 1 TLS, [n.d.].
  - International Women's Writing Guild, The. 1 newsletter, Jan. 26, 1980.
  - Ippolitto, Donna. 1 TLS, 1 ALS, July 19, 1976; Aug. 8, 1981.
  - Isaacs, Elizabeth. Correspondence, July 1968 to Nov. 1979.
  - Islas, Arturo. 1 ALS, April 16, 1980.
  - Jacobs, Terry. 1 wedding invitation, Sept. 13, 1980.
  - Jacobson, Yvonne. Correspondence et al., Feb. 1980 to Feb. 1982.Includes other correspondence.
  - Hillman, Tony. 1 ALS, [Feb. 10, 1982]. (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Hitzman, Mr. and Mrs. Donald. 1 wedding invitation, Aug. 20, 1983.
  - Hobart, Billie. 1 printed C, Sept. 1983.
  - Holt, Achilles M. 1 ALS, May 23, 1974.
  - Homberger, Eric. 1 ALS, June 1, 1979.
  - Hoss, Della. Correspondence et al., May 1977 to [July 1983].Includes a review of The Return of Martin Guerre.
  - Hoss, Peter T. 1 TLS et al., July 23, 1979.
  - House, Kay. Correspondence, July 1976 to Jan. 1977. (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Humblott, Mme. 1 ALS, July 30, 1967.
  - Humblott, Gene. Correspondence, March 1980 to May 1981.
  - Hunter College. Correspondence, Feb. 1977 to April 1977.
  - Huntington, The. 1 TLS, Jan. 4, 1980.
  - Huttner, Richard. 2 TLS, Feb. 3, 1978; April 4, 1978.Includes 1 carbon TLS from Janet Lewis Winters.
  - Jansen, George. Correspondence et al., [Dec. 1977] to March 1982. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Jansen, Judi. 1 ALS, Jan. 1, [1982].
  - Jansen-Brewer, Faith. 1 printed C, 1 ALS, [Dec. 6, 1981]; Jan. 2, 1983.
  - Janssens, G. 1 TLS, Sept. 20, 1968.
  - Jobil, F. 1 ALS, Aug. 6, 1971.
  - Johnson, Ginny. 1 ALS, Feb. 4, 1984.
  - Johnson, Marian A. 1 TLS, May 15, 1967.Includes 1 brochure, Writing Creativity & Craft.
  - Jones, Evan. 1 ALS, Sept. 18, 1968.
  - Jumper, Will C. 1 TLS, Sept. 25, 1978.
  - Kallet, Tony. 1 TLS, Feb. 10, 1976. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Kawaguchi, Aiko. 1 ALS, [May 7, 1982].
  - Kay, Ellen. 1 ALS, [Dec. 14, 1984].
  - Keen, Noah. 1 TLS, 1 ALS, Jan. 27, 1970; Feb. 1, 1970.
  - Keithley, Mary Zoe. 1 TLS, 1 ALS, Feb. 21, 1980; March 19, 1980.
  - Kiley, Joan. 1 ALS, June 29, 1983.
  - Killoh, Ellen Peck. 1 TLS, Dec. 1, 1975.
  - Kirby, David Vance. 1 TLS, May 19, 1976.
  - Kizer, Benjamin. 2 TLS, April 22, 1967; May 1, 1967.
  - Kizer, Carolyn. Correspondence et al. Aug. 1964 to July 1967. (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Kjellmark, Eric. Correspondence, April 1976 to June 1976.Includes ph. of poem Hawkeye and 1 passage of a novel by James Fennimore Cooper.
  - Klene, Mimi. 1 ALS, Oct. 6, 1975.
  - Knepler, Henry. 1 TLS, 1 ALS, June 2, 1966; Oct. 7, 1976.
  - Kodansha International, Ltd. 1 TLS, Sept. 26, 1969.
  - Koeninig, Dee. 1 birth announcement, Sept. 20, 1983.
  - Koenig, Frederick. 1 Wedding invitation, Aug. 7, [n.y.].
  - Koenig, Mr. and Mrs. Frederick Otto. 1 wedding invitation, [July 22, 1977].
  - Koessler, Betty. 1 ALS, Jan. 2, 1965.
  - Koessler, Maximilian. 2 TLS, July 25, 1963; Aug. 12, 1963.
  - Koneg, Heidi. 1 ALS, Sept. 8, 1976.
  - Koolish, Lynda. 1 TLS, Jan. 18, 1977.Includes book proposal of Continuing Presences: Twentieth Century American Women Poets. (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Kraft, James. 1 TLS, March 4, 1976.
  - Krendel, Tamara. Correspondence, April 1981 to July 1982.
  - Kronfeld, Marion. Correspondence, Christmas 1965 to March 1977. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Kuepper, Hedwige. 1 ACS, [Aug. 23, 1982].
  - Labadie, Jim. 1 TLS, June 27, 1978.Includes 1 unopened letter from Janet Lewis Winters. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Lago, Mary M. Correspondence, Nov. 1969 to June 1975.
  - Lake George Opera Festival. 1 TLS, 1 ALS, May 12, 1978; June 1, 1979.
  - Langbaum, Robert. 1 TCS, Jan. 18, 1980.
  - La Tour. 1 ptd. LS, [n.d.].
  - Leider, Emily. Correspondence, Aug. 1980 to Feb. 1982. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Les Presses de la Cité. 1 TLS, April 4, 1968.
  - Lesemann, Marjorie. Correspondence, [July 1979] to Oct. 1983.
  - Lesemann, Maurice. Correspondence, July 1967 to May 1978.Includes other correspondence.
  - -----. Correspondence, Nov. 1978 to March 1980. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Levin, David. Correspondence et al., Nov. 1971 to Aug. 1983.
  - Lew, Ying. 1 TLS, 1 ALS, Nov. 15, 1975; Dec. 28, 1976. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Lewis, Anne. Correspondence, April 1976 to Jan. 1982.Includes 1 photo.